Petra, open the door!
¡Petra, abre la puerta!
I must take you for a check-up today!
¡Debo llevarte a un chequeo hoy!
I told you it's pointless, no matter how many times you come!
¡No tiene sentido, por muchas veces que vengas!
Why do you think I'm coming all the way out here?
¿Por qué crees que vine hasta acá?
Nobody asked you to!
¡Nadie te lo pidió!
You stubborn, cranky woman!
¡Mujer testaruda y malhumorada!
Look who's talking, you quack doctor!
¡Mira quién habla, curandero!
I haven't seen a doctor since I was born,
No he visto a un médico desde que nací,
but I'm doing just fine as you can see.
pero estoy bien, como puedes ver.
-Just get out of here! -Why you…
- ¡Ya vete de aquí! - Te…
Doctor, we have an emergency!
¡Doctor, tenemos una emergencia!
Dr. Schumann!
¡Dr. Schumann!
What happened?
¿Qué pasó?
The drunkard Fink got hit on the highway!
¡Atropellaron al borracho Fink en la autopista!
What?
¿Qué?
Is he conscious?
¿Está consciente?
The guy who carried him in is treating him now.
El tipo que lo trajo lo está tratando.
Huh?
¿Qué?
Someone who was passing by is checking his injury.
Alguien que iba pasando está revisando su herida.
What do you mean?
¿Qué quieres decir?
What is the meaning of this?
¿Qué significa esto?
When I told him you were out on a house call, he just…
Cuando le dije que fue a una visita a domicilio, lo…
And you let him treat him?
¿Dejaste que lo tratara?
I'm sorry. I tried to stop him, but he said the patient might choke.
Perdón.
So he asked me to give him first aid at least.
así que me pidió darle primeros auxilios.
I have no idea. He left without leaving a name.
No tengo idea. Se fue sin decir su nombre.
Oh, he did write something on the chart.
Escribió algo en la ficha.
"The patient said not to take him to a doctor,
"El paciente dijo que no lo llevara al médico,
because he had no money."
porque no tenía dinero.
"So please use this money to pay for his medical fees."
Use este dinero para pagar sus gastos médicos".
God damn it!
¡Maldita sea!
What did the guy look like?
¿Cómo era el tipo?
He was Asian, and he had a boy with him.
Era asiático y andaba con un niño.
Um… What should we do about Mr. Fink's treatment?
¿Cómo tratamos al señor Fink?
Just leave him on the bed.
Déjalo en la cama.
But that man only did first aid…
Pero ese hombre solo le hizo primeros auxilios…
That wasn't just first aid.
No fueron solo primeros auxilios.
It was perfect.
Lo que hizo es perfecto.
Hey, Dieter.
Oye, Dieter,
I really can't have you keep following me like this.
no puedo permitir que me sigas así.
I cannot stay in one place,
No puedo quedarme en un lugar,
so you cannot go to school.
así que no puedes ir a la escuela.
You won't have any friends.
No tendrás amigos.
-I have a friend. -Who is that?
- Tengo un amigo. - ¿Quién es?
Tenma.
Tenma.
Was that you?
¿Fuiste tú?
Were you the one who meddled at my clinic?
¿Fuiste tú quien intervino en mi clínica?
Don't insult me!
¡No me insultes!
I'm well aware that Fink is a penniless drunkard!
¡Sé que Fink es un borracho sin dinero!
I've never considered taking money from him.
Nunca pensé en pedirle dinero.
Well, uh…
Ah, bueno…
You're probably some elite doctor from a famous hospital
Debes ser un doctor de primera de un hospital famoso
making yourself feel good with some charity work on your vacation.
que quiere sentirse mejor haciendo caridad en sus vacaciones.
-Hey. -Hey there.
- Hola.
-Let's go, Dieter. -What's up? Are you busy?
- Vamos, Dieter. - ¿Estás ocupado?
-Not at all. -Hey.
- Para nada. - Oye.
Listen to me when I'm talking!
- ¡Escúchame cuando te hablo! - Me disculpo, pero tenemos prisa.
Fink got involved in a hit-and-run.
Atropellaron a Fink.
That drunkard Fink?
¿Ese borracho de Fink?
Yeah.
Sí.
We're looking for any eyewitnesses.
Estamos buscando testigos.
Hey, Dr. Schumann.
Hola, Dr. Schumann.
How is Fink's condition?
¿Cómo está Fink?
He's alive enough. I'm more worried about his drinking problem.
Está vivo. Me preocupa más su problema con la bebida.
And you are?
¿Y tú quién eres?
Uh, I am…
Soy…
Ah!
¡Ah!
This is Dr. Chang.
Es el Dr. Chang.
He was my junior at my old college.
Estudiaba en mi universidad.
He stopped by our village during his vacation.
Pasó por nuestro pueblo en sus vacaciones.
Dr. Chang? Have we met before?
¿Doctor Chang? ¿No nos conocemos?
He treated Fink for me today,
Hoy trató a Fink por mí, ya que estaba en una visita a domicilio.
By the way, do you know where I went today?
Por cierto, ¿sabes dónde fui hoy?
Heinz, I was at your mother Petra's.
Heinz, estuve en casa de tu madre Petra.
My mom's?
¿Mi mamá?
You should tell her to come to the clinic.
Deberías decirle que vaya a la clínica.
She may need treatment immediately.
Quizá necesite tratamiento de inmediato.
That's impossible. That stubborn woman won't listen to anyone.
Eso es imposible. Esa mujer terca no escucha a nadie.
You sound like it's none of your business.
Suena como si no te importara.
Don't worry! My mom won't die that easily.
¡No se preocupe! Mi mamá no morirá tan fácilmente.
What…?
¿Qué?
Anyway, after raising me to this point,
De todos modos, después de criarme hasta este punto,
I don't think she has any regrets.
no creo que se arrepienta de nada.
What are you saying? Hey, wait!
¿Qué dices? ¡Oye, espera!
Petra has her own life to live!
¡Petra tiene su propia vida!
Why did you make up that lie?
¿Por qué inventó esa mentira?
Hmm?
¿Qué?
It's just to thank you for saving Fink.
Fue para agradecerte por salvar a Fink.
Without your swift treatment, he might have died.
Sin tu tratamiento rápido, podría haber muerto.
Thank you.
Gracias.
You turned white as a sheet when you saw the policeman.
Te pusiste blanco cuando viste al policía.
Are you…
Estás…
Well, never mind.
Bueno, no importa.
At least now, I'm sure you're not an elite doctor from a famous hospital.
Ahora sé que no eres un médico de primera de un hospital famoso.
Thank you very much.
Muchas gracias.
I don't know how to repay you.
No sé cómo pagarle.
Repay me?
¿Pagarme?
There is a way for you to repay me.
Hay una forma de pagarme.
Huh?
¿Qué?
Ouch!
¡Ay!
Your cast is a little off.
Su yeso está un poco mal.
It'll hurt a bit, but please bear with me.
Le dolerá un poco, pero tenga paciencia.
Ow!
¡Ay!
You'll be fine now.
Ahora estará bien.
You should be able to take it off after two weeks.
Deberías poder quitártelo en dos semanas.
Doctor, I made some nice apple brandy.
Doctor, hice un buen brandy de manzana.
How about a drink?
¿Qué tal un trago?
Don't say that when you're injured.
No digas eso cuando estás herido.
After you're healed, I can drink with you all night.
Cuando te cures, beberemos toda la noche.
You are making good progress.
Está progresando bien.
After five days, you can work on the farm.
En cinco días, puede trabajar en la granja.
Isn't that great, Mr. Schöne?
¿No es genial, señor Schöne?
Doctor, please take some potatoes with you.
Doctor, llévese unas papas.
They are very tasty this year.
Están muy sabrosas este año.
I'll come by next time with my truck and fill it up!
Vendré la próxima vez con mi camioneta y la llenaré.
Thanks for the help. My specialism is internal medicine.
Gracias por ayudar. Me especializo en medicina interna.
I try to do as much as I can outside my field,
Intento hacer todo lo que puedo fuera de mi campo,
but it's hard doing it on my own.
pero es difícil hacerlo solo.
It's wonderful.
Es maravilloso.
This village doesn't have much, but it's nice and peaceful.
Este pueblo no tiene mucho, pero es agradable y pacífico.
I'm not talking about the village.
No hablo del pueblo.
You are well-loved by the people here.
La gente de aquí lo quiere mucho.
And you genuinely love them yourself.
Y usted los quiere de verdad.
Huh, love?
¿Qué? ¿Quererlos?
I lost that feeling a long time ago.
Perdí ese sentimiento hace mucho tiempo.
I'm just doing my job.
Solo hago mi trabajo.
Come with me to one more house.
Acompáñame a una casa más.
This is a tough one.
Esta es difícil.
You don't know when to give up, huh?
No sabes cuándo rendirte, ¿no?
Yeah, I'll come back as many times as it takes.
Sí, regresaré todas las veces que sean necesarias.
It'll be the same every time!
¡Siempre responderé lo mismo!
Just get out of here, quack doctor!
¡Sal de aquí, curandero!
That's what it's like.
Así es.
This is the mother of that policeman. She got sick during farm work.
Esta es la madre de ese policía.
I tried to take her to the clinic,
Traté de llevarla a la clínica,
but she said she was fine and came back before we got to the clinic.
pero dijo que estaba bien y regresó antes de que llegáramos a la clínica.
It's worrisome.
Es preocupante.
Yeah.
Sí.
Shall I try to convince her?
¿Intento convencerla?
It might be the same, but…
Quizá no haga diferencia, pero…
Are you still dawdling about out there?
¿Sigues perdiendo el tiempo ahí afuera?
Where I dawdle is none of your business!
¡No es asunto tuyo lo que haga!
Now, now. If you keep yelling like that,
Ya, si sigue gritando así,
nobody would want to come out.
nadie querrá salir.
I'm taking you to the clinic, no matter what!
¡Te llevaré, pase lo que pase!
I can't lose my reason for living!
¡No puedo perder mi razón de vivir!
What?
¿Qué?
Ah… No…
Ah… No quiero perder a alguien con quien me gusta discutir.
And… I wouldn't be able to eat the goulash she makes.
Y…
Sir, your face is all red.
Señor, tiene la cara roja.
What? You brat!
¿Qué? ¡Mocoso!
Please open up, Petra.
Por favor, abra, Petra.
What? Another doctor?
¿Qué? ¿Otro doctor?
It's useless! That stubborn woman.
¡Es inútil! Esa mujer es testaruda.
Why do you hate doctors?
¿Por qué odia a los doctores?
Why? Huh!
¿Por qué?
They play with people's bodies,
¡Juegan con los cuerpos de la gente y todos se creen una especie de dios!
Gods, huh?
Dioses, ¿eh?
Sometimes I wish I were a god.
A veces desearía ser un dios.
Even though we try our best, mistakes will always happen.
Aunque hagamos todo lo posible, siempre habrá errores.
I wish I could heal people perfectly like a god.
Ojalá pudiera curar a la gente perfectamente como un dios.
Whenever I see a patient,
Cuando veo a un paciente,
I always get nervous and hesitate.
siempre me pongo nervioso y dudo.
Please. Let us see your face, at least.
Por favor, déjenos verle la cara, al menos.
Are you making goulash?
¿Está haciendo goulash?
Why? Do you like goulash?
¿Por qué? ¿Te gusta el goulash?
Yes.
Sí.
It seems like your goulash is Dr. Schumann's favorite.
Parece que su goulash es el favorito del Dr. Schumann.
That's the first time I've heard about it.
Es la primera vez que lo oigo.
Every time I made it for him, he only sat there and ate.
Cada vez que se lo hacía, solo se sentaba y comía.
He's just shy.
Es tímido.
This looks really good!
¡Se ve muy bien!
Goodness. My shoulders hurt so much,
Cielos.
but I have to get dinner ready.
pero tengo que preparar la cena.
Petra, can you touch your chest with your chin?
Petra, ¿puede tocarse el pecho con la barbilla?
Of course I can! See?
Claro que sí. ¿Ve?
Excuse me.
Permiso.
I can fit four fingers in.
Caben cuatro dedos.
Is that some kind of spell?
¿Es algún tipo de hechizo?
How is she?
¿Cómo está?
I'm afraid it could be a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Puede que sea una hemorragia subaracnoidea.
What?
¿Qué?
Petra!
¡Petra!
Here's a fax about a murder suspect.
Llegó un fax sobre un sospechoso de homicidio.
Make more copies.
Haz más copias.
How is your mother? I heard she fainted three days ago.
¿Cómo está tu madre? Oí que se desmayó hace tres días.
She's fine.
Está bien.
She won't die, even if you kill her.
¡No morirá aunque la maten!
We're within 72 hours of her first spasm.
Estamos a 72 horas de su primer espasmo.
There's not much time, so we need to operate immediately.
Hay poco tiempo. Debemos operarla de inmediato.
I wonder if a helicopter would make it…
¿Llegará un helicóptero…?
Can you do the operation?
¿Puedes operarla?
-What? -Please.
- ¿Qué? - Por favor.
If you can do the surgery, please do it.
Si puedes operarla, por favor, hazlo.
If not, I…
Si no,
I will lose another loved one because of my own actions.
perderé a otro ser querido por mis propias acciones.
Are you sure you saw Kenzo Tenma?
- ¿Seguro que viste a Kenzo Tenma? - Sí.
Good. He must still be close.
Bien. Aún debe estar cerca.
Roadblocks on the highway!
- ¡Pongan controles en la carretera! - ¡Será un gran logro atraparlo!
Y… Yes, sir!
¡Sí, señor!
All officers, emergency deployment!
¡Hagan un despliegue de emergencia!
Alright! If all goes well, I'll get a promotion.
¡Muy bien! Si todo sale bien, conseguiré un ascenso.
Hey, Heinz. A call for you.
Oye, Heinz, tienes una llamada.
This is Heinz.
Habla Heinz.
Oh, hello, nurse.
Hola, enfermera.
Mom collapsed again?
¿Mi mamá colapsó otra vez?
If only I had forced her
Si tan solo la hubiera obligado
to check into a national hospital after the first spasm.
a ingresar a un hospital nacional después del primer espasmo.
You're my only hope, Dr. Tenma.
Eres mi única esperanza, Dr. Tenma.
As I suspected, it's a middle cerebral artery bifurcation aneurysm.
Como pensé, es un aneurisma de bifurcación de la arteria cerebral media.
Damn it. We don't have a surgical microscope
Maldición, no tenemos un microscopio quirúrgico
or a craniotome here.
ni un taladro craneal.
If you have cerebral artery clips, I can try operating without a microscope.
Si tiene clips de aneurismas, puedo operar sin microscopio.
Even for you, it'll be difficult.
Incluso para ti, será difícil.
I can only give it a try.
Solo puedo intentarlo.
If her cerebral aneurysm ruptures again, she might not be able to live.
Si su aneurisma cerebral se rompe de nuevo, quizá no sobreviva.
This is happening again, and it's all my fault.
Esto está pasando de nuevo, y todo es mi culpa.
What's wrong, Dr. Schumann?
¿Qué pasa, Dr. Schumann?
You're not talking like someone who's taking care of an entire village alone.
No habla como alguien que se ocupa de todo un pueblo solo.
I don't know what happened in the past,
No sé qué pasó en el pasado,
but we can only do our best for the patient as doctors.
pero solo podemos hacer lo mejor para la paciente como doctores.
Hey, boy. Is Dr. Schumann inside?
Hola, niño. ¿El Dr. Schumann está adentro?
Yeah, he's doing a surgery.
Sí, está haciendo una cirugía.
Surgery? On my mother?
¿Una cirugía? ¿A mi madre?
He didn't send her to the city hospital, but he's doing it here?
¿La hará aquí en vez de enviarla a la ciudad?
Don't worry. Tenma is here.
No se preocupe. Tenma está aquí.
Did you say "Tenma"?
¿Dijiste "Tenma"?
How are her blood pressure and pulse?
¿Presión sanguínea y pulso?
Blood pressure is 126/84 and pulse rate is 88.
La presión arterial es de 126/84 y el pulso es de 88.
Amazing.
Increíble.
He didn't even have a craniotome, but he opened her skull so quickly.
Ni siquiera tenía un taladro craneal, pero le abrió el cráneo muy rápido.
What are you doing?
¿Qué haces?
As you can see, we're operating on your mother.
Como ves, estamos operando a tu madre.
What are you doing with that gun?
- ¿Qué haces con la pistola? - ¡Manos arriba, Tenma!
Tenma!
¡Tenma!
We're in the middle of a surgery. Are you trying to kill your mother?
Estamos en medio de la cirugía. ¿Quieres matar a tu madre?
He's the one who's trying to kill her!
¡Él es quien intenta matarla!
That guy has been running away because he's a murder suspect!
¡Ese tipo está huyendo porque es sospechoso de homicidio!
What?
¿Qué?
He killed a man in Heidelberg,
Mató a un hombre en Heidelberg
and he's a suspect for the serial murders of middle-aged couples.
y es sospechoso de asesinar a varias parejas.
I never thought I'd find him here.
Nunca esperé encontrarlo aquí.
I'm grateful that my mom has given me this chance.
Agradezco que mi mamá me haya dado esta oportunidad.
Come on and put your hands up. Otherwise, I'll shoot you!
Vamos, levanta las manos. ¡Si no, te dispararé!
Get the hell out of here!
¡Lárgate de aquí!
You're bringing in germs.
Traes gérmenes.
If infection enters this room, your mother could get meningitis and it'll be fatal!
Si entra una infección, a tu madre le dará meningitis,
Then, hurry and stop the surgery!
¡Apúrate y detén la cirugía!
Are you trying to get your mother killed?
¿Quieres que tu madre muera?
Your mother is suffering from a subarachnoid hemorrhage.
Tu madre sufre una hemorragia subaracnoidea.
She first collapsed three days ago.
Se desmayó hace tres días.
If we don't do the surgery now, it'll be too late!
¡Si no hacemos la cirugía ahora, será muy tarde!
Hurry and get out!
¡Ya vete!
Is my mom a hostage?
¿Mi mamá es una rehén?
Are you trying to use my mom as a hostage and run away from here?
¿Intentas usar a mi mamá como rehén y huir de aquí?
Cerebral artery clips and forceps.
Clips de aneurismas y fórceps.
I need the clips and forceps!
- ¡Necesito clips de aneurismas y fórceps! - ¡Sí!
That's my mother!
¡Es mi madre!
I won't let anyone hurt my mom!
¡No dejaré que nadie la lastime!
Yes. Petra is your mother.
Sí, Petra es tu madre.
But what have you done for her in the past five years?
Pero ¿qué has hecho por ella en los últimos cinco años?
Ever since you moved into the town, did you ever visit her?
¿La has visitado desde que te mudaste a la ciudad?
After she brought you up all these years,
Después de que te crio todos estos años,
what have you done for her?
¿qué has hecho por ella?
Listen! People you cherish will be gone someday.
¡Escucha!
Do you still remember the taste of your mother's goulash?
¿Aún recuerdas el sabor del goulash de tu madre?
Even now, Petra still makes your share out of habit.
Incluso ahora, Petra sigue haciendo tu porción por costumbre.
And I eat the leftovers.
Y yo me como las sobras.
It's delicious, just excellent.
Es delicioso, simplemente excelente.
Dr. Tenma is trying to save your mother,
El Dr. Tenma intenta salvar a tu madre
and he's doing everything he can.
y hace todo lo posible.
If you still want to taste that goulash, get out of here quietly!
Si quieres probar ese goulash, ¡vete en silencio!
I told you it'd be fine since Tenma is here.
Le dije que estaría bien, gracias a Tenma.
Blood pressure is 140/86 and pulse rate is 82.
La presión arterial es 140/86 y el pulso es 82.
Vital signs are great.
Los signos vitales son geniales.
Ms. Pionier, you should get some rest as well.
Srta. Pionier, debería descansar también.
But you two are…
Pero ustedes dos están…
I'm fine. You go ahead and have some rest.
Estoy bien. Ve a descansar un poco.
Thank you. I'll go then.
Gracias. Iré entonces.
Good work today.
Buen trabajo hoy.
Dr. Tenma, you should sleep as well.
Dr. Tenma, también deberías dormir.
I'm fine.
Estoy bien.
You did that difficult surgery from beginning to end.
Hiciste esa cirugía difícil de principio a fin.
I have to keep watch, just in case.
Debo vigilarla, por si acaso.
I want to see her get better,
Quiero verla mejorar,
so that you can propose to her.
para que pueda pedirle matrimonio.
What are you talking about, propose to my mom?
¿Quién le pedirá matrimonio?
What? I thought you were asleep.
¿Qué? Pensé que estabas dormido.
How can I sleep before I take him in?
¿Cómo puedo dormir antes de llevármelo?
Never mind that. What did he mean? Doctor, are you--
Olvídelo. ¿Qué quiso decir? Doctor, ¿está…?
Don't be stupid!
¡No seas estúpido!
Don't be stupid…
No seas estúpido…
I'm not the kind of man who can propose to someone.
No soy el tipo de hombre que puede pedirle matrimonio a alguien.
I never cared to talk to the patient when I was in the university hospital.
Nunca quise hablar con los pacientes
I only thought about how to secure my position in the hospital,
Solo pensaba en cómo asegurar mi puesto en el hospital,
and I wrote papers for the director to get into his faction.
y le escribí artículos al director para entrar a su facción.
Finally, I married the director's daughter.
Finalmente, me casé con la hija del director.
Even afterwards, I followed the road to career success.
Incluso después, seguí buscando éxito profesional.
I never paid any attention to my wife.
Nunca le presté atención a mi esposa.
If I actually looked at her, I would've noticed something was wrong.
Si la hubiera mirado, habría notado que algo andaba mal.
If I was a real doctor…
Si fuera un doctor de verdad…
She had suffered from cold-like symptoms for a long time.
Sufrió de síntomas de resfrío por mucho tiempo.
If I'd paid more attention, I would've caught it.
Si hubiera puesto más atención, lo habría descubierto.
It was liver failure.
Fue una falla hepática.
In her final moments, she said…
En sus últimos momentos, dijo…
You have finally looked at me.
Al fin me miraste.
I have no right to love anyone.
No tengo derecho a amar a nadie.
That's not true.
No es cierto.
You do look at people.
Sí mira a la gente.
You've been watching over everyone here.
Ha estado cuidando a todos aquí.
Because you did, Petra is saved.
Porque hizo eso, Petra está a salvo.
Are you still taking him away?
¿Aún te lo quieres llevar?
This man who risked his own life to save your mother's?
¿Al que arriesgó su vida para salvar a tu madre?
Do you still think he's a murderer?
¿Aún crees que es un asesino?
Heinz!
¡Heinz!
This is Heinz. The chief, please.
Habla Heinz. El jefe, por favor.
Sir, I'm sorry. It was someone else.
Señor, lo siento. Era otra persona.
Please call off the roadblock.
Cancele el control.
The man I saw wasn't Tenma. It was a man called Dr. Chang.
El hombre que vi no era Tenma. Era un hombre llamado Dr. Chang.
I mistook him because he's Asian.
Lo confundí porque es asiático.
I'm very sorry. Please forgive me.
Lo siento mucho. Por favor, perdóneme.
The doctor at the national hospital was surprised.
El doctor del hospital nacional estaba sorprendido.
I suppose he never thought he'd see such amazing treatment
Supongo que nunca pensó que vería un tratamiento tan increíble
done in a rural clinic like ours.
en una clínica rural como esta.
Doctor!
¡Doctor!
Are you just going to let the young doctor go like that?
¿Va a dejar que el doctor joven se vaya así?
I wanted to treat him to something good, but he's left!
¡Quería invitarlo a comer algo rico, pero se fue!
Tenma!
¡Tenma!
Don't go!
¡No te vayas!
You're safe in this village! You don't have to leave.
¡Estás a salvo aquí! No tienes que irte.
Dr. Schumann.
Dr. Schumann.
Dieter, don't you like it here as well?
Dieter, ¿no te gusta estar aquí también?
Yeah. I guess this village might be good for you, Dieter.
Sí, supongo que este pueblo puede ser bueno para ti, Dieter.
Not just for Dieter.
No solo para Dieter.
We can protect you from the police if you stay in the village.
Podemos protegerte de la policía si te quedas.
Please take care of the people here with me.
Por favor, cuida a la gente de aquí conmigo.
This village needs you.
Este pueblo te necesita.
But I have to leave.
Pero tengo que irme.
Why?
¿Por qué?
Please take care of Dieter.
Por favor, cuide a Dieter.
Tenma, I'm coming with you!
¡Tenma, iré contigo!
If you stay here, we can save so many lives!
¡Si te quedas aquí, podemos salvar muchas vidas!
Please, let us work together!
¡Por favor, trabajemos juntos!
Save many lives?
¿Salvar muchas vidas?
I have… to kill a man.
Tengo que…
What?
¿Qué?
Tenma!
¡Tenma!
What did you mean, Tenma?
¿Qué quisiste decir, Tenma?
You are not someone who's capable of that!
¡No eres capaz de eso!
You work so hard to save the lives of others!
¡Trabajas tanto para salvarles la vida a otros!
He's leaving.
Se irá.
No matter what, he is leaving.
Pase lo que pase, se irá.
-Dieter, go ahead. -Huh?
- Dieter, ve. - ¿Qué?
If you're with Tenma, he won't stray from his path.
Si estás con Tenma, no se desviará de su camino.
Watch out for Tenma, okay?
Cuida a Tenma, ¿sí?